Guide to the Women's Center, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Women's Center, Yale University, records
1969-2014
RU 1130
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
4
(4 boxes)
The Women's Center, Yale University, records consists of administrative files, event records, publications, staffer journals and subject files from 1969 to 2014.
Yale University. Yale Women's Center
Scope and Contents
The Women's Center, Yale University, records consists of administrative files, event records, publications, staffer journals and subject files from 1969 to 2014.
General
Forms part of Yale Record Group 9-B (YRG 9-B), Records of deputy, associate, and assistant deans of Yale College.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collection requires the permission of the Women's Center. Contact the University Archives for more information.
Biographical / Historical
Founded in 1970, the Yale Women's Center is an umbrella organization for groups on Yale's campus and beyond that deal with issues of gender and sexuality.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged alphabetically by series: Adminstrative files, Events, Publications, Reports, Staffer journals, and Subject files.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The records were tranferred from the Yale Women's Center, 2014.
Yale University. Yale Women's Center
- Records, Accession 2014-A-071
  - Administrative files
    - Activities at Dwight Hall, 1992-2000 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Advertising and promotion, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Advisory Board notes, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Amy Rossborough Fellowship, 2000-2001 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Budgets, 2000-2001 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Budgets and financial management files, 1987-1999 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Budgets and proposals, 2003-2004 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Business Coordinator duties report, 2003-2004 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Business Manager duties outline, 2000-2001 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Center proposals-funding and facilities, 1976-1999 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Coordinating Board reports and photographs, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Coordinating Board reports and supporting materials, 1998-2000 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Coordinating Committee meeting minutes, 1987-1993 (Box 1, Folder 13-14)
    - Coordinating Committee meeting minutes, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence with alumnae, Circa 1995, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Meeting minutes and organizational files, 1982-1999 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Stationery and letterhead, Undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Events
    - 30th anniversary of co-education at Yale, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Art show photographs, Undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Guestbook: dedication of the Women's Table, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - "How We See": art show for Women's Art at Yale series, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - "Multi-Media Works by Women": art show for Women's Art at Yale series, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Special projects-Women's Center retreat, 1995-2000 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Women's Week: notebook, Circa 1989 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Publications
    - "Aurora"
      - Administrative files
        - Business records, 1980-1982 (Box 1, Folder 26)
        - Correspondence, 1977-2002 (Box 1, Folder 27)
        - Flyers, Undated (Box 1, Folder 28)
        - Submissions with editorial notes, Undated (Box 1, Folder 29)
      - Issues
        - Special issues: "Zirkus", volume 2 number 1, 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 30)
        - 1981 fall-1982 winter (Box 1, Folder 31)
        - Special issues: "Dialectics", 1983 fall-1984 spring (Box 1, Folder 32)
        - Special issues: "Tender Buttons", 1984 fall-1985 spring (Box 1, Folder 33)
        - 1985 spring-1986 fall (Box 1, Folder 34)
        - 1987 spring-1988 fall (Box 1, Folder 35)
        - Tenth anniversary issue, 1989 spring-1990 fall (Box 1, Folder 36)
        - 1991 winter-1993 spring (Box 1, Folder 37)
        - 1995 winter, 2002 winter (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - "Calhoun Literary Arts Magazine" (CLAM): "Turns Two" issue, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - "Celebrating Women"
      - Art (graphics to use), 1990 (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - Business files, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 3)
      - Proofs, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 4-6)
      - Submissions, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 7-8)
    - "Girl Empowered Magazine (GEM)", 2003 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - "My Tongue", 1990 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - "30 Years: Women Artists at Yale", 2000 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - "Type": business files and issues, 1999-2000 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - "Women of the Ivy League", 1986, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - "The Yale Graduate Professional" (YGP), 1978 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - "Yale Women's Center Presents: Feminism Today", 2014 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Reports
    - "My Turn: Woman's Guide to Returning to School in the New Haven Area", 1981 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Faculty of Arts and Sciences Advisory Committee report on the education of women, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - President's Committee to Monitor Recruitment and Retention of Disabled, Minority, and Women Faculty: first report, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - "In Defense of Affirmative Action", 1996 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Staffer journals
    - 1981-1983 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - 1983-1985 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - 1985-1986 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - 1987-1988 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - 1988 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - 1989 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - 1989-1990 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - 1990-1991 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - 1991-1993 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - 1992-1994 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - 1994-1996 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - 1996-2003 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - 2003-2007 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - 2005-2008 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Subject files
    - Abortion/reproductive rights, 1977-1990 (Box 3, Folder 8-9)
    - Affirmative action, 1976-1981 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - AIDS, 1986-1990 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Alexander v. Yale, 1977-1980 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Arts, 1969-1990 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Athletics, 1976-1985 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Children/families, 1975-1999 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Coalition for an Educated Choice, 1985-1986 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Community of Women Athletes, 1987-1988 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Crime, Circa 1989, undated (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Discrimination (sex and race) at Yale, 1975-1980 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Domestic violence, 1986-1989, undated (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Ecology and feminism, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Equal Rights Amendment (ERA), 1978-1982 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Faculty diversity, 1984-1989 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Family Protection Act, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Grievance Board (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Gymnastics, 1986 Fall (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Health
      - Health at Yale, 2012, undated (Box 3, Folder 27)
      - Health services-ob/gyn, 1974-1975 (Box 3, Folder 28)
      - Health services-ob/gyn reviews, 1974-1976 (Box 3, Folder 29)
      - Health services-ob/gyn reviews, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 1)
      - Health services-midwives, 1973-1983 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Katie Koestner-Take Back the Night, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Legislation and prisons, 1983-1987 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Lesbian/gay issues, 1978-2010 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Media, 1978-1984 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Men, 1988, undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Military, 1979-1988 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - New Haven Women's Center, 1977-2000 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - National Organization for Women (NOW), 1977-1990 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Planned Parenthood, 1979-1995 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Politicians, 1989, undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Politics, 1976-1990 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Political organizations (women), 1980-1983 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Pornography, 1979-1987 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Race issues at Yale, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Racism, 1979-1985 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Rape, 1976-1985 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Religion, 1982-2002 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Reproductive rights, 1981-1986 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Science and technology, 1979-1987 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Search for female dean of Yale College, 1975-1977 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Sexual harassment, 1996-1998, undated (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Sexual harassment complaint against French 115, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Take back the night, 1981-2000 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Take back the night-testimonies, 2013 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Third world women, 1979-1980 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Tenure, 1977-1999 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Tenure Action Committee, 1997-1999 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Upperclassmen mentoring freshwomen, 1979-1997 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Walden peer counseling, Undated (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Welfare teach-in packet, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Women's Caucus, 1977-1980 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Women's centers (other), 1979-1999 (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Women's Self-Defense Alliance, 1988, undated (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Women's studies, 1971-1995 (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Yale-women faculty, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 37)